<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<sst xmlns="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/spreadsheetml/2006/main" count="2799" uniqueCount="1045"><si><t>Year</t></si><si><t>Accessible Balance</t></si><si><t>Percent of Accessible Balance</t></si><si><t>Debt</t></si><si><t>Interest Rate:</t></si><si><t>Accumulation Phase</t></si><si><t>Years of Service</t></si><si><t>Distribution Phase</t></si><si><t>Return</t></si><si><t>Debt Limit:</t></si><si><t>Current Debt:</t></si><si><t>Home Value:</t></si><si><t>Provisional Income</t></si><si><t>Payroll Tax</t></si><si><t>Gross Income</t></si><si><t>Net Worth</t></si><si><t>Single</t></si><si><t>Head of Household</t></si><si><t>Married Filing Separately</t></si><si><t>Married Filing Jointly</t></si><si><t>Long Term Capital Gains and Qualified Dividends</t></si><si><t>Ordinary Income</t></si><si><t>Taxable Income over</t></si><si><t>Tax Addon</t></si><si><t>Filing Status:</t></si><si><t>SS Base</t></si><si><t>SS Tax Addon</t></si><si><t>SS Percent Taxable</t></si><si><t>Code</t></si><si><t>Self-Employment Income</t></si><si><t>Real Estate Tax</t></si><si><t>Withdrawals</t></si><si><t>Qualified Home</t></si><si><t>Delayed Credit Per Year:</t></si><si><t>Time Table</t></si><si><t>Employer-Sponsored Retirement Plans</t></si><si><t>Default Wage Inflation:</t></si><si><t>Default Consumer Price Inflation:</t></si><si><t>Birth Date:</t></si><si><t>Bend Point</t></si><si><t>Benefit Percent</t></si><si><t>SS Primary Insurance Amount (PIA)</t></si><si><t>Taxable Income</t></si><si><t>Earnings Required for Work Credits (dollars)</t></si><si><t>Credits Needed</t></si><si><t>Full Retirement Age:</t></si><si><t>Primary Benefits Filing Age:</t></si><si><t>Auxiliary Benefits Filing Age:</t></si><si><t>Deemed Filing Age:</t></si><si><t>Maximum of Four Credits a Year:</t></si><si><t>Personal Exemption:</t></si><si><t>Tax Rates (percent)</t></si><si><t>Social Security (Old-Age, Survivors, and Disability Insurance)</t></si><si><t>Employers and Employees, each:</t></si><si><t>Medicare (Hospital Insurance)</t></si><si><t>Social Security (OASDI) Program Rates &amp; Limits</t></si><si><t>One Work Credit:</t></si><si><t>Primary Benefit:</t></si><si><t>Auxiliary Benefit:</t></si><si><t>Recalculated Primary Benefit:</t></si><si><t>Recalculated Auxiliary Benefit:</t></si><si><t>Primary Benefit Months Withheld:</t></si><si><t>Auxiliary Benefit Months Withheld:</t></si><si><t>Wage IDX</t></si><si><t>CP IDX</t></si><si><t>COLA</t></si><si><t>Bend Point 1</t></si><si><t>Bend Point 2</t></si><si><t>Age</t></si><si><t>Filing Date Prorate:</t></si><si><t>APW</t></si><si><t>PIA</t></si><si><t>FRW</t></si><si><t>PBW</t></si><si><t>ABW</t></si><si><t>AET Lower</t></si><si><t>AET Upper</t></si><si><t>Excess Family Benefit</t></si><si><t>Self-Employment Tax</t></si><si><t>SS RIB Reduction Factors, Withholdings, and Benefits (Nominal w/ COLA)</t></si><si><t>PBW
∩
E</t></si><si><t>PBW
∩
F</t></si><si><t>ABW
∩
EE</t></si><si><t>ABW
∩
EF</t></si><si><t>ABW
∩
FE</t></si><si><t>ABW
∩
FF</t></si><si><t>APW
∩
E</t></si><si><t>PB
MMAX
E</t></si><si><t>PB
MMAX
F</t></si><si><t>AB
MMAX
E</t></si><si><t>AB
MMAX
F</t></si><si><t>ABW
∩
ER</t></si><si><t>ABW
∩
FR</t></si><si><t>RFW</t></si><si><t>AB
MMAX
R</t></si><si><t>Base Year:</t></si><si><t>SS RIB Coefficient Matrix</t></si><si><t>Social Security Wage Base</t></si><si><t>RET PB RCM</t></si><si><t>RET AB RCM</t></si><si><t>RET WHPCT E</t></si><si><t>Payroll/SE</t></si><si><t>State</t></si><si><t>Federal</t></si><si><t>Taxable Ordinary Income</t></si><si><t>Ordinary Income Tax</t></si><si><t>Capital Gains Tax</t></si><si><t>Home Insurance</t></si><si><t>Social Security Retirement Insurance Benefits (RIB)</t></si><si><t>Pre-RET Family Benefit</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    (at your option) any later version.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    along with this program.  If not, see &lt;http://www.gnu.org/licenses/&gt;.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    GNU Affero General Public License for more details.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    You should have received a copy of the GNU Affero General Public License</t></si><si><t>mailto:larry.blumer@retireator.org</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    This program is free software: you can redistribute it and/or modify</t></si><si><t>This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,</t></si><si><t>but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of</t></si><si><t>MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the</t></si><si><t>along with this program.  If not, see &lt;http://www.gnu.org/licenses/&gt;.</t></si><si><t>Retireator is free software: you can redistribute it and/or modify</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    it under the terms of the GNU Affero General Public License as published</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    by the Free Software Foundation, either version 3 of the License, or</t></si><si><t>it under the terms of the GNU Affero General Public License as published</t></si><si><t>by the Free Software Foundation, either version 3 of the License, or</t></si><si><t>any later version.</t></si><si><t>GNU Affero General Public License for more details.</t></si><si><t>You should have received a copy of the GNU Affero General Public License</t></si><si><t>GNU AFFERO GENERAL PUBLIC LICENSE</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">                       Version 3, 19 November 2007</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve"> Copyright (C) 2007 Free Software Foundation, Inc. &lt;http://fsf.org/&gt;</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve"> Everyone is permitted to copy and distribute verbatim copies</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve"> of this license document, but changing it is not allowed.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">                            Preamble</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  The GNU Affero General Public License is a free, copyleft license for</t></si><si><t>software and other kinds of works, specifically designed to ensure</t></si><si><t>cooperation with the community in the case of network server software.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  The licenses for most software and other practical works are designed</t></si><si><t>to take away your freedom to share and change the works.  By contrast,</t></si><si><t>our General Public Licenses are intended to guarantee your freedom to</t></si><si><t>share and change all versions of a program--to make sure it remains free</t></si><si><t>software for all its users.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  When we speak of free software, we are referring to freedom, not</t></si><si><t>price.  Our General Public Licenses are designed to make sure that you</t></si><si><t>have the freedom to distribute copies of free software (and charge for</t></si><si><t>them if you wish), that you receive source code or can get it if you</t></si><si><t>want it, that you can change the software or use pieces of it in new</t></si><si><t>free programs, and that you know you can do these things.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  Developers that use our General Public Licenses protect your rights</t></si><si><t>with two steps: (1) assert copyright on the software, and (2) offer</t></si><si><t>you this License which gives you legal permission to copy, distribute</t></si><si><t>and/or modify the software.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  A secondary benefit of defending all users' freedom is that</t></si><si><t>improvements made in alternate versions of the program, if they</t></si><si><t>receive widespread use, become available for other developers to</t></si><si><t>incorporate.  Many developers of free software are heartened and</t></si><si><t>encouraged by the resulting cooperation.  However, in the case of</t></si><si><t>software used on network servers, this result may fail to come about.</t></si><si><t>The GNU General Public License permits making a modified version and</t></si><si><t>letting the public access it on a server without ever releasing its</t></si><si><t>source code to the public.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  The GNU Affero General Public License is designed specifically to</t></si><si><t>ensure that, in such cases, the modified source code becomes available</t></si><si><t>to the community.  It requires the operator of a network server to</t></si><si><t>provide the source code of the modified version running there to the</t></si><si><t>users of that server.  Therefore, public use of a modified version, on</t></si><si><t>a publicly accessible server, gives the public access to the source</t></si><si><t>code of the modified version.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  An older license, called the Affero General Public License and</t></si><si><t>published by Affero, was designed to accomplish similar goals.  This is</t></si><si><t>a different license, not a version of the Affero GPL, but Affero has</t></si><si><t>released a new version of the Affero GPL which permits relicensing under</t></si><si><t>this license.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  The precise terms and conditions for copying, distribution and</t></si><si><t>modification follow.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">                       TERMS AND CONDITIONS</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  0. Definitions.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  "This License" refers to version 3 of the GNU Affero General Public License.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  "Copyright" also means copyright-like laws that apply to other kinds of</t></si><si><t>works, such as semiconductor masks.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  "The Program" refers to any copyrightable work licensed under this</t></si><si><t>License.  Each licensee is addressed as "you".  "Licensees" and</t></si><si><t>"recipients" may be individuals or organizations.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  To "modify" a work means to copy from or adapt all or part of the work</t></si><si><t>in a fashion requiring copyright permission, other than the making of an</t></si><si><t>exact copy.  The resulting work is called a "modified version" of the</t></si><si><t>earlier work or a work "based on" the earlier work.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  A "covered work" means either the unmodified Program or a work based</t></si><si><t>on the Program.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  To "propagate" a work means to do anything with it that, without</t></si><si><t>permission, would make you directly or secondarily liable for</t></si><si><t>infringement under applicable copyright law, except executing it on a</t></si><si><t>computer or modifying a private copy.  Propagation includes copying,</t></si><si><t>distribution (with or without modification), making available to the</t></si><si><t>public, and in some countries other activities as well.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  To "convey" a work means any kind of propagation that enables other</t></si><si><t>parties to make or receive copies.  Mere interaction with a user through</t></si><si><t>a computer network, with no transfer of a copy, is not conveying.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  An interactive user interface displays "Appropriate Legal Notices"</t></si><si><t>to the extent that it includes a convenient and prominently visible</t></si><si><t>feature that (1) displays an appropriate copyright notice, and (2)</t></si><si><t>tells the user that there is no warranty for the work (except to the</t></si><si><t>extent that warranties are provided), that licensees may convey the</t></si><si><t>work under this License, and how to view a copy of this License.  If</t></si><si><t>the interface presents a list of user commands or options, such as a</t></si><si><t>menu, a prominent item in the list meets this criterion.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  1. Source Code.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  The "source code" for a work means the preferred form of the work</t></si><si><t>for making modifications to it.  "Object code" means any non-source</t></si><si><t>form of a work.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  A "Standard Interface" means an interface that either is an official</t></si><si><t>standard defined by a recognized standards body, or, in the case of</t></si><si><t>interfaces specified for a particular programming language, one that</t></si><si><t>is widely used among developers working in that language.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  The "System Libraries" of an executable work include anything, other</t></si><si><t>than the work as a whole, that (a) is included in the normal form of</t></si><si><t>packaging a Major Component, but which is not part of that Major</t></si><si><t>Component, and (b) serves only to enable use of the work with that</t></si><si><t>Major Component, or to implement a Standard Interface for which an</t></si><si><t>implementation is available to the public in source code form.  A</t></si><si><t>"Major Component", in this context, means a major essential component</t></si><si><t>(kernel, window system, and so on) of the specific operating system</t></si><si><t>(if any) on which the executable work runs, or a compiler used to</t></si><si><t>produce the work, or an object code interpreter used to run it.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  The "Corresponding Source" for a work in object code form means all</t></si><si><t>the source code needed to generate, install, and (for an executable</t></si><si><t>work) run the object code and to modify the work, including scripts to</t></si><si><t>control those activities.  However, it does not include the work's</t></si><si><t>System Libraries, or general-purpose tools or generally available free</t></si><si><t>programs which are used unmodified in performing those activities but</t></si><si><t>which are not part of the work.  For example, Corresponding Source</t></si><si><t>includes interface definition files associated with source files for</t></si><si><t>the work, and the source code for shared libraries and dynamically</t></si><si><t>linked subprograms that the work is specifically designed to require,</t></si><si><t>such as by intimate data communication or control flow between those</t></si><si><t>subprograms and other parts of the work.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  The Corresponding Source need not include anything that users</t></si><si><t>can regenerate automatically from other parts of the Corresponding</t></si><si><t>Source.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  The Corresponding Source for a work in source code form is that</t></si><si><t>same work.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  2. Basic Permissions.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  All rights granted under this License are granted for the term of</t></si><si><t>copyright on the Program, and are irrevocable provided the stated</t></si><si><t>conditions are met.  This License explicitly affirms your unlimited</t></si><si><t>permission to run the unmodified Program.  The output from running a</t></si><si><t>covered work is covered by this License only if the output, given its</t></si><si><t>content, constitutes a covered work.  This License acknowledges your</t></si><si><t>rights of fair use or other equivalent, as provided by copyright law.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  You may make, run and propagate covered works that you do not</t></si><si><t>convey, without conditions so long as your license otherwise remains</t></si><si><t>in force.  You may convey covered works to others for the sole purpose</t></si><si><t>of having them make modifications exclusively for you, or provide you</t></si><si><t>with facilities for running those works, provided that you comply with</t></si><si><t>the terms of this License in conveying all material for which you do</t></si><si><t>not control copyright.  Those thus making or running the covered works</t></si><si><t>for you must do so exclusively on your behalf, under your direction</t></si><si><t>and control, on terms that prohibit them from making any copies of</t></si><si><t>your copyrighted material outside their relationship with you.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  Conveying under any other circumstances is permitted solely under</t></si><si><t>the conditions stated below.  Sublicensing is not allowed; section 10</t></si><si><t>makes it unnecessary.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  3. Protecting Users' Legal Rights From Anti-Circumvention Law.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  No covered work shall be deemed part of an effective technological</t></si><si><t>measure under any applicable law fulfilling obligations under article</t></si><si><t>11 of the WIPO copyright treaty adopted on 20 December 1996, or</t></si><si><t>similar laws prohibiting or restricting circumvention of such</t></si><si><t>measures.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  When you convey a covered work, you waive any legal power to forbid</t></si><si><t>circumvention of technological measures to the extent such circumvention</t></si><si><t>is effected by exercising rights under this License with respect to</t></si><si><t>the covered work, and you disclaim any intention to limit operation or</t></si><si><t>modification of the work as a means of enforcing, against the work's</t></si><si><t>users, your or third parties' legal rights to forbid circumvention of</t></si><si><t>technological measures.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  4. Conveying Verbatim Copies.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  You may convey verbatim copies of the Program's source code as you</t></si><si><t>receive it, in any medium, provided that you conspicuously and</t></si><si><t>appropriately publish on each copy an appropriate copyright notice;</t></si><si><t>keep intact all notices stating that this License and any</t></si><si><t>non-permissive terms added in accord with section 7 apply to the code;</t></si><si><t>keep intact all notices of the absence of any warranty; and give all</t></si><si><t>recipients a copy of this License along with the Program.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  You may charge any price or no price for each copy that you convey,</t></si><si><t>and you may offer support or warranty protection for a fee.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  5. Conveying Modified Source Versions.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  You may convey a work based on the Program, or the modifications to</t></si><si><t>produce it from the Program, in the form of source code under the</t></si><si><t>terms of section 4, provided that you also meet all of these conditions:</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    a) The work must carry prominent notices stating that you modified</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    it, and giving a relevant date.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    b) The work must carry prominent notices stating that it is</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    released under this License and any conditions added under section</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    7.  This requirement modifies the requirement in section 4 to</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    "keep intact all notices".</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    c) You must license the entire work, as a whole, under this</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    License to anyone who comes into possession of a copy.  This</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    License will therefore apply, along with any applicable section 7</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    additional terms, to the whole of the work, and all its parts,</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    regardless of how they are packaged.  This License gives no</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    permission to license the work in any other way, but it does not</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    invalidate such permission if you have separately received it.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    d) If the work has interactive user interfaces, each must display</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    Appropriate Legal Notices; however, if the Program has interactive</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    interfaces that do not display Appropriate Legal Notices, your</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    work need not make them do so.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  A compilation of a covered work with other separate and independent</t></si><si><t>works, which are not by their nature extensions of the covered work,</t></si><si><t>and which are not combined with it such as to form a larger program,</t></si><si><t>in or on a volume of a storage or distribution medium, is called an</t></si><si><t>"aggregate" if the compilation and its resulting copyright are not</t></si><si><t>used to limit the access or legal rights of the compilation's users</t></si><si><t>beyond what the individual works permit.  Inclusion of a covered work</t></si><si><t>in an aggregate does not cause this License to apply to the other</t></si><si><t>parts of the aggregate.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  6. Conveying Non-Source Forms.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  You may convey a covered work in object code form under the terms</t></si><si><t>of sections 4 and 5, provided that you also convey the</t></si><si><t>machine-readable Corresponding Source under the terms of this License,</t></si><si><t>in one of these ways:</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    a) Convey the object code in, or embodied in, a physical product</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    (including a physical distribution medium), accompanied by the</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    Corresponding Source fixed on a durable physical medium</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    customarily used for software interchange.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    b) Convey the object code in, or embodied in, a physical product</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    (including a physical distribution medium), accompanied by a</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    written offer, valid for at least three years and valid for as</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    long as you offer spare parts or customer support for that product</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    model, to give anyone who possesses the object code either (1) a</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    copy of the Corresponding Source for all the software in the</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    product that is covered by this License, on a durable physical</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    medium customarily used for software interchange, for a price no</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    more than your reasonable cost of physically performing this</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    conveying of source, or (2) access to copy the</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    Corresponding Source from a network server at no charge.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    c) Convey individual copies of the object code with a copy of the</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    written offer to provide the Corresponding Source.  This</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    alternative is allowed only occasionally and noncommercially, and</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    only if you received the object code with such an offer, in accord</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    with subsection 6b.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    d) Convey the object code by offering access from a designated</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    place (gratis or for a charge), and offer equivalent access to the</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    Corresponding Source in the same way through the same place at no</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    further charge.  You need not require recipients to copy the</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    Corresponding Source along with the object code.  If the place to</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    copy the object code is a network server, the Corresponding Source</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    may be on a different server (operated by you or a third party)</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    that supports equivalent copying facilities, provided you maintain</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    clear directions next to the object code saying where to find the</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    Corresponding Source.  Regardless of what server hosts the</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    Corresponding Source, you remain obligated to ensure that it is</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    available for as long as needed to satisfy these requirements.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    e) Convey the object code using peer-to-peer transmission, provided</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    you inform other peers where the object code and Corresponding</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    Source of the work are being offered to the general public at no</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    charge under subsection 6d.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  A separable portion of the object code, whose source code is excluded</t></si><si><t>from the Corresponding Source as a System Library, need not be</t></si><si><t>included in conveying the object code work.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  A "User Product" is either (1) a "consumer product", which means any</t></si><si><t>tangible personal property which is normally used for personal, family,</t></si><si><t>or household purposes, or (2) anything designed or sold for incorporation</t></si><si><t>into a dwelling.  In determining whether a product is a consumer product,</t></si><si><t>doubtful cases shall be resolved in favor of coverage.  For a particular</t></si><si><t>product received by a particular user, "normally used" refers to a</t></si><si><t>typical or common use of that class of product, regardless of the status</t></si><si><t>of the particular user or of the way in which the particular user</t></si><si><t>actually uses, or expects or is expected to use, the product.  A product</t></si><si><t>is a consumer product regardless of whether the product has substantial</t></si><si><t>commercial, industrial or non-consumer uses, unless such uses represent</t></si><si><t>the only significant mode of use of the product.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  "Installation Information" for a User Product means any methods,</t></si><si><t>procedures, authorization keys, or other information required to install</t></si><si><t>and execute modified versions of a covered work in that User Product from</t></si><si><t>a modified version of its Corresponding Source.  The information must</t></si><si><t>suffice to ensure that the continued functioning of the modified object</t></si><si><t>code is in no case prevented or interfered with solely because</t></si><si><t>modification has been made.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  If you convey an object code work under this section in, or with, or</t></si><si><t>specifically for use in, a User Product, and the conveying occurs as</t></si><si><t>part of a transaction in which the right of possession and use of the</t></si><si><t>User Product is transferred to the recipient in perpetuity or for a</t></si><si><t>fixed term (regardless of how the transaction is characterized), the</t></si><si><t>Corresponding Source conveyed under this section must be accompanied</t></si><si><t>by the Installation Information.  But this requirement does not apply</t></si><si><t>if neither you nor any third party retains the ability to install</t></si><si><t>modified object code on the User Product (for example, the work has</t></si><si><t>been installed in ROM).</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  The requirement to provide Installation Information does not include a</t></si><si><t>requirement to continue to provide support service, warranty, or updates</t></si><si><t>for a work that has been modified or installed by the recipient, or for</t></si><si><t>the User Product in which it has been modified or installed.  Access to a</t></si><si><t>network may be denied when the modification itself materially and</t></si><si><t>adversely affects the operation of the network or violates the rules and</t></si><si><t>protocols for communication across the network.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  Corresponding Source conveyed, and Installation Information provided,</t></si><si><t>in accord with this section must be in a format that is publicly</t></si><si><t>documented (and with an implementation available to the public in</t></si><si><t>source code form), and must require no special password or key for</t></si><si><t>unpacking, reading or copying.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  7. Additional Terms.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  "Additional permissions" are terms that supplement the terms of this</t></si><si><t>License by making exceptions from one or more of its conditions.</t></si><si><t>Additional permissions that are applicable to the entire Program shall</t></si><si><t>be treated as though they were included in this License, to the extent</t></si><si><t>that they are valid under applicable law.  If additional permissions</t></si><si><t>apply only to part of the Program, that part may be used separately</t></si><si><t>under those permissions, but the entire Program remains governed by</t></si><si><t>this License without regard to the additional permissions.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  When you convey a copy of a covered work, you may at your option</t></si><si><t>remove any additional permissions from that copy, or from any part of</t></si><si><t>it.  (Additional permissions may be written to require their own</t></si><si><t>removal in certain cases when you modify the work.)  You may place</t></si><si><t>additional permissions on material, added by you to a covered work,</t></si><si><t>for which you have or can give appropriate copyright permission.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  Notwithstanding any other provision of this License, for material you</t></si><si><t>add to a covered work, you may (if authorized by the copyright holders of</t></si><si><t>that material) supplement the terms of this License with terms:</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    a) Disclaiming warranty or limiting liability differently from the</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    terms of sections 15 and 16 of this License; or</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    b) Requiring preservation of specified reasonable legal notices or</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    author attributions in that material or in the Appropriate Legal</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    Notices displayed by works containing it; or</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    c) Prohibiting misrepresentation of the origin of that material, or</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    requiring that modified versions of such material be marked in</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    reasonable ways as different from the original version; or</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    d) Limiting the use for publicity purposes of names of licensors or</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    authors of the material; or</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    e) Declining to grant rights under trademark law for use of some</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    trade names, trademarks, or service marks; or</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    f) Requiring indemnification of licensors and authors of that</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    material by anyone who conveys the material (or modified versions of</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    it) with contractual assumptions of liability to the recipient, for</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    any liability that these contractual assumptions directly impose on</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    those licensors and authors.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  All other non-permissive additional terms are considered "further</t></si><si><t>restrictions" within the meaning of section 10.  If the Program as you</t></si><si><t>received it, or any part of it, contains a notice stating that it is</t></si><si><t>governed by this License along with a term that is a further</t></si><si><t>restriction, you may remove that term.  If a license document contains</t></si><si><t>a further restriction but permits relicensing or conveying under this</t></si><si><t>License, you may add to a covered work material governed by the terms</t></si><si><t>of that license document, provided that the further restriction does</t></si><si><t>not survive such relicensing or conveying.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  If you add terms to a covered work in accord with this section, you</t></si><si><t>must place, in the relevant source files, a statement of the</t></si><si><t>additional terms that apply to those files, or a notice indicating</t></si><si><t>where to find the applicable terms.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  Additional terms, permissive or non-permissive, may be stated in the</t></si><si><t>form of a separately written license, or stated as exceptions;</t></si><si><t>the above requirements apply either way.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  8. Termination.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  You may not propagate or modify a covered work except as expressly</t></si><si><t>provided under this License.  Any attempt otherwise to propagate or</t></si><si><t>modify it is void, and will automatically terminate your rights under</t></si><si><t>this License (including any patent licenses granted under the third</t></si><si><t>paragraph of section 11).</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  However, if you cease all violation of this License, then your</t></si><si><t>license from a particular copyright holder is reinstated (a)</t></si><si><t>provisionally, unless and until the copyright holder explicitly and</t></si><si><t>finally terminates your license, and (b) permanently, if the copyright</t></si><si><t>holder fails to notify you of the violation by some reasonable means</t></si><si><t>prior to 60 days after the cessation.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  Moreover, your license from a particular copyright holder is</t></si><si><t>reinstated permanently if the copyright holder notifies you of the</t></si><si><t>violation by some reasonable means, this is the first time you have</t></si><si><t>received notice of violation of this License (for any work) from that</t></si><si><t>copyright holder, and you cure the violation prior to 30 days after</t></si><si><t>your receipt of the notice.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  Termination of your rights under this section does not terminate the</t></si><si><t>licenses of parties who have received copies or rights from you under</t></si><si><t>this License.  If your rights have been terminated and not permanently</t></si><si><t>reinstated, you do not qualify to receive new licenses for the same</t></si><si><t>material under section 10.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  9. Acceptance Not Required for Having Copies.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  You are not required to accept this License in order to receive or</t></si><si><t>run a copy of the Program.  Ancillary propagation of a covered work</t></si><si><t>occurring solely as a consequence of using peer-to-peer transmission</t></si><si><t>to receive a copy likewise does not require acceptance.  However,</t></si><si><t>nothing other than this License grants you permission to propagate or</t></si><si><t>modify any covered work.  These actions infringe copyright if you do</t></si><si><t>not accept this License.  Therefore, by modifying or propagating a</t></si><si><t>covered work, you indicate your acceptance of this License to do so.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  10. Automatic Licensing of Downstream Recipients.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  Each time you convey a covered work, the recipient automatically</t></si><si><t>receives a license from the original licensors, to run, modify and</t></si><si><t>propagate that work, subject to this License.  You are not responsible</t></si><si><t>for enforcing compliance by third parties with this License.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  An "entity transaction" is a transaction transferring control of an</t></si><si><t>organization, or substantially all assets of one, or subdividing an</t></si><si><t>organization, or merging organizations.  If propagation of a covered</t></si><si><t>work results from an entity transaction, each party to that</t></si><si><t>transaction who receives a copy of the work also receives whatever</t></si><si><t>licenses to the work the party's predecessor in interest had or could</t></si><si><t>give under the previous paragraph, plus a right to possession of the</t></si><si><t>Corresponding Source of the work from the predecessor in interest, if</t></si><si><t>the predecessor has it or can get it with reasonable efforts.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  You may not impose any further restrictions on the exercise of the</t></si><si><t>rights granted or affirmed under this License.  For example, you may</t></si><si><t>not impose a license fee, royalty, or other charge for exercise of</t></si><si><t>rights granted under this License, and you may not initiate litigation</t></si><si><t>(including a cross-claim or counterclaim in a lawsuit) alleging that</t></si><si><t>any patent claim is infringed by making, using, selling, offering for</t></si><si><t>sale, or importing the Program or any portion of it.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  11. Patents.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  A "contributor" is a copyright holder who authorizes use under this</t></si><si><t>License of the Program or a work on which the Program is based.  The</t></si><si><t>work thus licensed is called the contributor's "contributor version".</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  A contributor's "essential patent claims" are all patent claims</t></si><si><t>owned or controlled by the contributor, whether already acquired or</t></si><si><t>hereafter acquired, that would be infringed by some manner, permitted</t></si><si><t>by this License, of making, using, or selling its contributor version,</t></si><si><t>but do not include claims that would be infringed only as a</t></si><si><t>consequence of further modification of the contributor version.  For</t></si><si><t>purposes of this definition, "control" includes the right to grant</t></si><si><t>patent sublicenses in a manner consistent with the requirements of</t></si><si><t>this License.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  Each contributor grants you a non-exclusive, worldwide, royalty-free</t></si><si><t>patent license under the contributor's essential patent claims, to</t></si><si><t>make, use, sell, offer for sale, import and otherwise run, modify and</t></si><si><t>propagate the contents of its contributor version.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  In the following three paragraphs, a "patent license" is any express</t></si><si><t>agreement or commitment, however denominated, not to enforce a patent</t></si><si><t>(such as an express permission to practice a patent or covenant not to</t></si><si><t>sue for patent infringement).  To "grant" such a patent license to a</t></si><si><t>party means to make such an agreement or commitment not to enforce a</t></si><si><t>patent against the party.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  If you convey a covered work, knowingly relying on a patent license,</t></si><si><t>and the Corresponding Source of the work is not available for anyone</t></si><si><t>to copy, free of charge and under the terms of this License, through a</t></si><si><t>publicly available network server or other readily accessible means,</t></si><si><t>then you must either (1) cause the Corresponding Source to be so</t></si><si><t>available, or (2) arrange to deprive yourself of the benefit of the</t></si><si><t>patent license for this particular work, or (3) arrange, in a manner</t></si><si><t>consistent with the requirements of this License, to extend the patent</t></si><si><t>license to downstream recipients.  "Knowingly relying" means you have</t></si><si><t>actual knowledge that, but for the patent license, your conveying the</t></si><si><t>covered work in a country, or your recipient's use of the covered work</t></si><si><t>in a country, would infringe one or more identifiable patents in that</t></si><si><t>country that you have reason to believe are valid.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  If, pursuant to or in connection with a single transaction or</t></si><si><t>arrangement, you convey, or propagate by procuring conveyance of, a</t></si><si><t>covered work, and grant a patent license to some of the parties</t></si><si><t>receiving the covered work authorizing them to use, propagate, modify</t></si><si><t>or convey a specific copy of the covered work, then the patent license</t></si><si><t>you grant is automatically extended to all recipients of the covered</t></si><si><t>work and works based on it.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  A patent license is "discriminatory" if it does not include within</t></si><si><t>the scope of its coverage, prohibits the exercise of, or is</t></si><si><t>conditioned on the non-exercise of one or more of the rights that are</t></si><si><t>specifically granted under this License.  You may not convey a covered</t></si><si><t>work if you are a party to an arrangement with a third party that is</t></si><si><t>in the business of distributing software, under which you make payment</t></si><si><t>to the third party based on the extent of your activity of conveying</t></si><si><t>the work, and under which the third party grants, to any of the</t></si><si><t>parties who would receive the covered work from you, a discriminatory</t></si><si><t>patent license (a) in connection with copies of the covered work</t></si><si><t>conveyed by you (or copies made from those copies), or (b) primarily</t></si><si><t>for and in connection with specific products or compilations that</t></si><si><t>contain the covered work, unless you entered into that arrangement,</t></si><si><t>or that patent license was granted, prior to 28 March 2007.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  Nothing in this License shall be construed as excluding or limiting</t></si><si><t>any implied license or other defenses to infringement that may</t></si><si><t>otherwise be available to you under applicable patent law.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  12. No Surrender of Others' Freedom.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  If conditions are imposed on you (whether by court order, agreement or</t></si><si><t>otherwise) that contradict the conditions of this License, they do not</t></si><si><t>excuse you from the conditions of this License.  If you cannot convey a</t></si><si><t>covered work so as to satisfy simultaneously your obligations under this</t></si><si><t>License and any other pertinent obligations, then as a consequence you may</t></si><si><t>not convey it at all.  For example, if you agree to terms that obligate you</t></si><si><t>to collect a royalty for further conveying from those to whom you convey</t></si><si><t>the Program, the only way you could satisfy both those terms and this</t></si><si><t>License would be to refrain entirely from conveying the Program.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  13. Remote Network Interaction; Use with the GNU General Public License.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  Notwithstanding any other provision of this License, if you modify the</t></si><si><t>Program, your modified version must prominently offer all users</t></si><si><t>interacting with it remotely through a computer network (if your version</t></si><si><t>supports such interaction) an opportunity to receive the Corresponding</t></si><si><t>Source of your version by providing access to the Corresponding Source</t></si><si><t>from a network server at no charge, through some standard or customary</t></si><si><t>means of facilitating copying of software.  This Corresponding Source</t></si><si><t>shall include the Corresponding Source for any work covered by version 3</t></si><si><t>of the GNU General Public License that is incorporated pursuant to the</t></si><si><t>following paragraph.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  Notwithstanding any other provision of this License, you have</t></si><si><t>permission to link or combine any covered work with a work licensed</t></si><si><t>under version 3 of the GNU General Public License into a single</t></si><si><t>combined work, and to convey the resulting work.  The terms of this</t></si><si><t>License will continue to apply to the part which is the covered work,</t></si><si><t>but the work with which it is combined will remain governed by version</t></si><si><t>3 of the GNU General Public License.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  14. Revised Versions of this License.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  The Free Software Foundation may publish revised and/or new versions of</t></si><si><t>the GNU Affero General Public License from time to time.  Such new versions</t></si><si><t>will be similar in spirit to the present version, but may differ in detail to</t></si><si><t>address new problems or concerns.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  Each version is given a distinguishing version number.  If the</t></si><si><t>Program specifies that a certain numbered version of the GNU Affero General</t></si><si><t>Public License "or any later version" applies to it, you have the</t></si><si><t>option of following the terms and conditions either of that numbered</t></si><si><t>version or of any later version published by the Free Software</t></si><si><t>Foundation.  If the Program does not specify a version number of the</t></si><si><t>GNU Affero General Public License, you may choose any version ever published</t></si><si><t>by the Free Software Foundation.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  If the Program specifies that a proxy can decide which future</t></si><si><t>versions of the GNU Affero General Public License can be used, that proxy's</t></si><si><t>public statement of acceptance of a version permanently authorizes you</t></si><si><t>to choose that version for the Program.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  Later license versions may give you additional or different</t></si><si><t>permissions.  However, no additional obligations are imposed on any</t></si><si><t>author or copyright holder as a result of your choosing to follow a</t></si><si><t>later version.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  15. Disclaimer of Warranty.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  THERE IS NO WARRANTY FOR THE PROGRAM, TO THE EXTENT PERMITTED BY</t></si><si><t>APPLICABLE LAW.  EXCEPT WHEN OTHERWISE STATED IN WRITING THE COPYRIGHT</t></si><si><t>HOLDERS AND/OR OTHER PARTIES PROVIDE THE PROGRAM "AS IS" WITHOUT WARRANTY</t></si><si><t>OF ANY KIND, EITHER EXPRESSED OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO,</t></si><si><t>THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR</t></si><si><t>PURPOSE.  THE ENTIRE RISK AS TO THE QUALITY AND PERFORMANCE OF THE PROGRAM</t></si><si><t>IS WITH YOU.  SHOULD THE PROGRAM PROVE DEFECTIVE, YOU ASSUME THE COST OF</t></si><si><t>ALL NECESSARY SERVICING, REPAIR OR CORRECTION.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  16. Limitation of Liability.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  IN NO EVENT UNLESS REQUIRED BY APPLICABLE LAW OR AGREED TO IN WRITING</t></si><si><t>WILL ANY COPYRIGHT HOLDER, OR ANY OTHER PARTY WHO MODIFIES AND/OR CONVEYS</t></si><si><t>THE PROGRAM AS PERMITTED ABOVE, BE LIABLE TO YOU FOR DAMAGES, INCLUDING ANY</t></si><si><t>GENERAL, SPECIAL, INCIDENTAL OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES ARISING OUT OF THE</t></si><si><t>USE OR INABILITY TO USE THE PROGRAM (INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO LOSS OF</t></si><si><t>DATA OR DATA BEING RENDERED INACCURATE OR LOSSES SUSTAINED BY YOU OR THIRD</t></si><si><t>PARTIES OR A FAILURE OF THE PROGRAM TO OPERATE WITH ANY OTHER PROGRAMS),</t></si><si><t>EVEN IF SUCH HOLDER OR OTHER PARTY HAS BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF</t></si><si><t>SUCH DAMAGES.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  17. Interpretation of Sections 15 and 16.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  If the disclaimer of warranty and limitation of liability provided</t></si><si><t>above cannot be given local legal effect according to their terms,</t></si><si><t>reviewing courts shall apply local law that most closely approximates</t></si><si><t>an absolute waiver of all civil liability in connection with the</t></si><si><t>Program, unless a warranty or assumption of liability accompanies a</t></si><si><t>copy of the Program in return for a fee.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">                     END OF TERMS AND CONDITIONS</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">            How to Apply These Terms to Your New Programs</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  If you develop a new program, and you want it to be of the greatest</t></si><si><t>possible use to the public, the best way to achieve this is to make it</t></si><si><t>free software which everyone can redistribute and change under these terms.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  To do so, attach the following notices to the program.  It is safest</t></si><si><t>to attach them to the start of each source file to most effectively</t></si><si><t>state the exclusion of warranty; and each file should have at least</t></si><si><t>the "copyright" line and a pointer to where the full notice is found.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    &lt;one line to give the program's name and a brief idea of what it does.&gt;</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">    Copyright (C) &lt;year&gt;  &lt;name of author&gt;</t></si><si><t>Also add information on how to contact you by electronic and paper mail.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  If your software can interact with users remotely through a computer</t></si><si><t>network, you should also make sure that it provides a way for users to</t></si><si><t>get its source.  For example, if your program is a web application, its</t></si><si><t>interface could display a "Source" link that leads users to an archive</t></si><si><t>of the code.  There are many ways you could offer source, and different</t></si><si><t>solutions will be better for different programs; see section 13 for the</t></si><si><t>specific requirements.</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve">  You should also get your employer (if you work as a programmer) or school,</t></si><si><t>if any, to sign a "copyright disclaimer" for the program, if necessary.</t></si><si><t>For more information on this, and how to apply and follow the GNU AGPL, see</t></si><si><t>&lt;http://www.gnu.org/licenses/&gt;.</t></si><si><t>http://www.retireator.org</t></si><si><t>Rent:</t></si><si><t>Utilities:</t></si><si><t>Renter's Insurance:</t></si><si><t>Internet, Cable, Phone:</t></si><si><t xml:space="preserve"> Food and Entertainment:</t></si><si><t>Auto and Transportation:</t></si><si><t>Clothing:</t></si><si><t>Home Maintenance:</t></si><si><t>Auto Insurance:</t></si><si><t>Vacation and Travel:</t></si><si><t>Real Estate Tax:</t></si><si><t>Home Insurance:</t></si><si><t>Expenses</t></si><si><t>Surplus or Deficit</t></si><si><t>Life Insurance:</t></si><si><t>Charitable Donations:</t></si><si><t>Health Care:</t></si><si><t>Additional Retirement Income:</t></si><si><t>Self-Employment Expenses:</t></si><si><t>Dependent Care:</t></si><si><t>Passive Income:</t></si><si><t>Tax Deductible</t></si><si><t>RN</t></si><si><t>RO</t></si><si><t>Exempt</t></si><si><t>No</t></si><si><t>Surplus or Deficit:</t></si><si><t>Interest on Debt:</t></si><si><t>Present and Future Living Expenses</t></si><si><t>Pre-FICA Deductions 1:</t></si><si><t>Pre-FICA Deductions 2:</t></si><si><t>Match</t></si><si><t>Deductions</t></si><si><t>/year</t></si><si><t>Monthly Expenses (Real Dollars)</t></si><si><t>Other Appreciating Assets:</t></si><si><t>Epoch Year:</t></si><si><t>Additional Discretionary:</t></si><si><t>Passive Income</t></si><si><t>Marital Status:</t></si><si><t>Tax Index:</t></si><si><t>Self-Employment Retirement Plans</t></si><si><t>Company Match:</t></si><si><t>Before-Tax Balance:</t></si><si><t>After-Tax Balance:</t></si><si><t>Before-Tax Contribution (Traditional IRA):</t></si><si><t>After-Tax Contribution (Roth IRA):</t></si><si><t>Individual Retirement Plans</t></si><si><t>Qualified Distribution Age:</t></si><si><t>After-Tax Cost Basis:</t></si><si><t>Social Security Indexing</t></si><si><t>Medicare Wages</t></si><si><t>Social Security Wages</t></si><si><t>Base Year IDX</t></si><si><t>Work Credits</t></si><si><t>AIME</t></si><si><t>COLA IDX</t></si><si><t>RI</t></si><si><t>Pre-FICA Deductions</t></si><si><t>Before-Tax Contribution (Spousal IRA):</t></si><si><t>Dependents:</t></si><si><t>Medicare Wages SE</t></si><si><t>Social Security Wages SE</t></si><si><t>Traditional IRA</t></si><si><t>Roth IRA</t></si><si><t>Before-Tax Balance</t></si><si><t>After-Tax Balance</t></si><si><t>Total Income Taxes</t></si><si><t>Social Security Income</t></si><si><t>Taxable Capital Income</t></si><si><t>Non-Taxable Capital Income</t></si><si><t>Annual Cash Flow</t></si><si><t>Long Term Capital Gains</t></si><si><t>Short Term Capital Gains</t></si><si><t>Ordinary Income Table</t></si><si><t>Employer Income</t></si><si><t>TN</t></si><si><t>Core Account</t></si><si><t>Core (Non-Retirement) Account Balance:</t></si><si><t>Capital Income</t></si><si><t>FICA/Fed/State:1</t></si><si><t>Fed/State:1</t></si><si><t>Gross Taxable Income</t></si><si><t>Taxable SS Income</t></si><si><t>Household</t></si><si><t>Individual</t></si><si><t>Misc</t></si><si><t>Additional Retirement Income</t></si><si><t>Non-Deductible IRA Contrib</t></si><si><t>Deductible IRA Contrib</t></si><si><t>Deductible Expenses 1:</t></si><si><t>Deductible Expenses 2:</t></si><si><t>Effective Tax Rate</t></si><si><t>IRA Contrib</t></si><si><t>Taxable Passive Income</t></si><si><t>Taxable Active Income</t></si><si><t>Active Income</t></si><si><t>Active Income:</t></si><si><t>Social Security Income:</t></si><si><t>Average Monthly Cash Flow (Real Dollars)</t></si><si><t>Gross Income Excluding Capital Income:</t></si><si><t>A</t></si><si><t>Code:</t></si><si><t>D</t></si><si><t>Income Taxes:</t></si><si><t>Total Living Expenses:</t></si><si><t>Expenses:</t></si><si><t>Fully Ins Status</t></si><si><t>$</t></si><si><t>RET Income</t></si><si><t>N</t></si><si><t>Cost Basis</t></si><si><t>YIW</t></si><si><t>View Mode:</t></si><si><t>Show:</t></si><si><t>Shadow</t></si><si><t>Prorated</t></si><si><t>Deductible Mort Expenses 1</t></si><si><t>Deductible Mort Expenses 2</t></si><si><t>Total Mort Expenses</t></si><si><t>Default</t></si><si><t>Shadow AP</t></si><si><t>Shadow DP</t></si><si><t>Shadow TD</t></si><si><t>Default TD</t></si><si><t>years</t></si><si><t>Origination Date:</t></si><si><t>Original Balance:</t></si><si><t>Term:</t></si><si><t>Maximum Forecast Years:</t></si><si><t>Current Date Prorate:</t></si><si><t>Cost Basis:</t></si><si><t>401(k)/403(b)</t></si><si><t>SEP/SIMPLE/Solo 401(k)</t></si><si><t>Roth Solo 401(k)</t></si><si><t>Roth 401(k)/403(b)</t></si><si><t>Before-Tax Contribution (401(k)/403(b)):</t></si><si><t>Before-Tax Contribution (SEP/SIMPLE/Solo 401(k)):</t></si><si><t>After-Tax Contribution (Roth 401(k)/403(b)):</t></si><si><t>After-Tax Contribution (Roth Solo 401(k)):</t></si><si><t>Version Major:</t></si><si><t>Minor:</t></si><si><t>Retirement Date:</t></si><si><t>Home and Mortgage</t></si><si><t>Debt Interest</t></si><si><t>Default Tags</t></si><si><t>Miscellaneous 1:</t></si><si><t>Miscellaneous 2:</t></si><si><t>Miscellaneous 3:</t></si><si><t>Miscellaneous 4:</t></si><si><t>Miscellaneous 5:</t></si><si><t>Mortgage Payment:</t></si><si><t>Tax Factor</t></si><si><t>Savings Goal</t></si><si><t>Data Mode:</t></si><si><t>Target Gross Income</t></si><si><t>Target Savings Drawdown</t></si><si><t>Start Work Age:</t></si><si><t>DB Pension</t></si><si><t>Extra Payment:</t></si><si><t>Extra Payment</t></si><si><t>Principal Payment:</t></si><si><t>Interest Payment:</t></si><si><t>Life Expectancy:</t></si><si><t>Detailed Household Profile</t></si><si><t>Detailed Individual Profile(s)</t></si><si><t>Wage Inflation (AWI)</t></si><si><t>CP Inflation (CPI-W)</t></si><si><t>Employer Income / Retirement Plans:</t></si><si><t>Self-Employment Income / Retirement Plans:</t></si><si><t>Passive Income / Individual Retirement Plans:</t></si><si><t>Home / Mortgage:</t></si><si><t>Social Security Retirement Insurance Benefits:</t></si><si><t>Simulation Parameters</t></si><si><t>Initials (Yourself):</t></si><si><t>Initials (Spouse):</t></si><si><t>of Employer Income</t></si><si><t>of Self-Employment Income</t></si><si><t>+ Wage Inflation</t></si><si><t>of FAE</t></si><si><t>+ Price Inflation</t></si><si><t>DB Pension Final Average Earnings (FAE) Years Used:</t></si><si><t>Defined Benefit (DB) Pension Start Work Date:</t></si><si><t>DB Pension Benefit Percentage:</t></si><si><t>Error Message</t></si><si><t>EOF</t></si><si><t>Date is in the past</t></si><si><t>Invalid filing age</t></si><si><t>Only one auxiliary filing allowed</t></si><si><t>No filing age provided</t></si><si><t>Current Employer Income:</t></si><si><t>Current Self-Employment Income:</t></si><si><t>Current Passive Income:</t></si><si><t>Stop Year:</t></si><si><t>Current Year:</t></si><si><t>Balance</t></si><si><t>Adjusted Date:</t></si><si><t>Error evaluating formula</t></si><si><t>+/-</t></si><si><t>CDW</t></si><si><t>OFF</t></si><si><t>Adjust to system date:</t></si><si><t>Current Date:</t></si><si><t>IDXR</t></si><si><t>IDXN</t></si><si><t>Default Annual Increase:</t></si><si><t>months</t></si><si><t>Standard Deduction Amounts</t></si><si><t>Wage Inflation Multiplier</t></si><si><t>Basic</t></si><si><t>Parameter Mode:</t></si><si><t>FLTP</t></si><si><t>FLTV</t></si><si><t>Term needed (12 months or more)</t></si><si><t>FLT</t></si><si><t>Average Future Tax Rate</t></si><si><t>Annual Return Stocks</t></si><si><t>Annual Return Bonds</t></si><si><t>Default Annual Return on Stocks:</t></si><si><t>Investment Strategy:</t></si><si><t>Cash</t></si><si><t>Aggressive</t></si><si><t>Moderate</t></si><si><t>Conservative</t></si><si><t>QDI Percentage</t></si><si><t>Investment Strategies</t></si><si><t>Name</t></si><si><t>Rate of Return</t></si><si><t>Years to Retirement</t></si><si><t>Stocks</t></si><si><t>Bonds</t></si><si><t>Dynamic</t></si><si><t>Target Date Fund</t></si><si><t>Moderately Conservative</t></si><si><t>Moderately Aggressive</t></si><si><t>Moderate Growth</t></si><si><t>Bond Yield</t></si><si><t>Default Bond Yield:</t></si><si><t>Enter a valid date</t></si><si><t>Enter a valid percentage</t></si><si><t>Enter a valid number</t></si><si><t>Enter a valid number not equal to zero</t></si><si><t>Enter a valid percentage greater than zero</t></si><si><t>Exact age</t></si><si><t>Maximum Extended Forecast Years:</t></si><si><t>Guaranteed Term:</t></si><si><t>Annuity</t></si><si><t>Payment Terms:</t></si><si><t>Payment Rate:</t></si><si><t>Survivor Benefit:</t></si><si><t>Life</t></si><si><t>Fixed</t></si><si><t>Balance:</t></si><si><t>After-Tax Contribution:</t></si><si><t>P(1)</t></si><si><t>P(2)</t></si><si><t>Participation Rate:</t></si><si><t>Withdrawal</t></si><si><t>Deposit</t></si><si><t>Deferral Period</t></si><si><t>Guar Term</t></si><si><t>Variable ROR</t></si><si><t>Fixed ROR</t></si><si><t>Rollover</t></si><si><t>Annuity Contrib</t></si><si><t>Taxable Annuity Income</t></si><si><t>Non-Taxable Annuity Income</t></si><si><t>Annuity Income</t></si><si><t>Savings Contrib</t></si><si><t>Savings Contributions:</t></si><si><t>Enter a number greater than zero</t></si><si><t>AFF</t></si><si><t>AFV</t></si><si><t>DFF</t></si><si><t>DFV</t></si><si><t>AIR</t></si><si><t>Payment Prorate:</t></si><si><t>Rate Ceiling:</t></si><si><t>Rate Floor:</t></si><si><t>Spread Fee:</t></si><si><t>PYW</t></si><si><t>DFI</t></si><si><t>AIRI</t></si><si><t>AFI</t></si><si><t>Inflation Adjusted:</t></si><si><t>Weight</t></si><si><t>Nominal Rate of Return:</t></si><si><t>DB Pension Payout Option:</t></si><si><t>Core Account Rollover</t></si><si><t>Annuity Rollover</t></si><si><t>Payout</t></si><si><t>Spouse Deposit</t></si><si><t>State, Local, and Foreign Income Taxes:</t></si><si><t>None</t></si><si><t>Quadratic Coeff</t></si><si><t>Linear Coeff</t></si><si><t>Constant</t></si><si><t>Independent Variable</t></si><si><t>SS Taxable</t></si><si><t>Principal Balance</t></si><si><t>Principal Payment</t></si><si><t>Interest Payment</t></si><si><t>Home Equity</t></si><si><t>Nper</t></si><si><t>Payments</t></si><si><t>Arkansas</t></si><si><t>Alabama</t></si><si><t>Alaska</t></si><si><t>Arizona</t></si><si><t>California</t></si><si><t>Colorado</t></si><si><t>Connecticut</t></si><si><t>Delaware</t></si><si><t>Florida</t></si><si><t>Georgia</t></si><si><t>Hawaii</t></si><si><t>Idaho</t></si><si><t>Illinois</t></si><si><t>Indiana</t></si><si><t>Iowa</t></si><si><t>Kansas</t></si><si><t>Kentucky</t></si><si><t>Louisiana</t></si><si><t>Maine</t></si><si><t>Maryland</t></si><si><t>Massachusetts</t></si><si><t>Michigan</t></si><si><t>Minnesota</t></si><si><t>Mississippi</t></si><si><t>Missouri</t></si><si><t>Montana</t></si><si><t>Nebraska</t></si><si><t>Nevada</t></si><si><t>New Hampshire</t></si><si><t>New Jersey</t></si><si><t>New Mexico</t></si><si><t>New York</t></si><si><t>North Carolina</t></si><si><t>North Dakota</t></si><si><t>Ohio</t></si><si><t>Oklahoma</t></si><si><t>Oregon</t></si><si><t>Pennsylvania</t></si><si><t>Rhode Island</t></si><si><t>South Carolina</t></si><si><t>South Dakota</t></si><si><t>Tennessee</t></si><si><t>Texas</t></si><si><t>Utah</t></si><si><t>Vermont</t></si><si><t>Virginia</t></si><si><t>Washington</t></si><si><t>West Virginia</t></si><si><t>Wisconsin</t></si><si><t>Wyoming</t></si><si><t>District of Columbia</t></si><si><t>Effective Property Tax Rate</t></si><si><t>No parameter provided</t></si><si><t>Enable macros to begin the setup process.</t></si><si><t>Home Value</t></si><si><t>Number outside of expected range</t></si><si><t>Origination Date</t></si><si><t>Adj Nper</t></si><si><t>Date is out of range</t></si><si><t>Default AP</t></si><si><t>Long-Term Care / Disability Insurance:</t></si><si><t>Male Death Probability</t></si><si><t>Male Life Expectancy</t></si><si><t>Female Death Probability</t></si><si><t>Female Life Expectancy</t></si><si><t>Social Security 2015 Period Life Table</t></si><si><t>Male Life Probability</t></si><si><t>Female Life Probability</t></si><si><t>Principal Limit Factor:</t></si><si><t>HECM</t></si><si><t>Interest</t></si><si><t>Lump Sum</t></si><si><t>Copyright© 2015-2020 Larry Blumer, Jr.</t></si><si><t>FHFA Max Conforming Loan Limit:</t></si></sst>